Hayeong Song

Georgia Tech Mobile: (404) 421-1064 TSRB 334, 85 5th St NW, Email: hsong300@gatech.edu

Atlanta, GA 30308 Website: https://www.cc.gatech.edu/~hsong300/about

Summary

My research interests are Data Science, Human-Computer Interaction, and Information Visualization. My research is focused on designing intelligent systems that can support users to analyze data and make data accessible to users by leveraging different machine learning models and drawing upon techniques from mixed-initiative.

I have experience in front/back end development and data visualization. I use a mixed-methods approach to inform design direction and develop products.

Education

PhD Computer Science, Georgia Institute of Technology, Advised by Dr. John Stasko

Aug 2018 - Present

M.S. Computer Science, University of Colorado Boulder, Advised by Dr. Danielle Albers Szafir

2016 - 2018

B.S. Computer Science, Handong Global University,

2012-2016

Publications

Hayeong Song & Danielle Albers Szafir. "Where's My Data? Evaluating Visualizations with Missing Data." IEEE Transactions on Visualizations and Computer Graphics, 2019. In Proceedings of IEEE VIS 2018.

Hayeong Song, Bahador Saket, & John Stasko "Evaluating the Effects of Visualizing Missing Values on Data Exploration." IEEE Transactions on Visualizations and Computer Graphics, 2020.

Hayeong Song, Yu Fu, Bahador Saket, & John Stasko "Understanding the Effects of Visualizing Missing Values on Data Exploration" IEEE Transactions on Visualizations and Computer Graphics, 2021.

Hayeong Song "Measuring the Role of Visualization on Missing Values in Time Series Data" University of Colorado Boulder, Computer Science Master's Thesis, 2018.

Experience

Research Intern at Microsoft Research

May 2021 - Present

Machine Teaching for Video AI, Mentors: Peter Bodik & Gonzalo Ramos

 Worked on improving Video AI tool (Pixie) by leveraging ML models and visualization to help users to train computer vision models easily.

Research Assistant, Georgia Institute of Technology

Aug 2018 - Present

Information Interfaces Research Group, Advisor: Professor John Stasko

- Implemented a multimodal drawing tool that supports speech and touch interactions.
- Conducted a user study to test effective speech activation techniques for a multimodal user interface.
- Built a visualization tool that leverages different ML interpolation methods and visualization techniques for users who have to analyze and make decisions with an incomplete dataset.
- Investigated and explored mobile designs for self-trackers to improve a current design that can better support personal data analysis.

Haveong Song 2

Research Assistant, University of Colorado, Boulder

VisuaLab, Advisor: Professor Danielle Albers Szafir

• Analyzed Tweets using sentiment analysis, topic modeling, and time-series analysis with machine learning and natural language processing models.

- Built visualization dashboard for social media for data analysis results.
- Conducted crowdsourced studies testing impact of visualization and imputation on missing data.

Internship at Dabarun Software

Jan 2015 - Feb 2015

Feb 2017- June 2018

- Implemented the chatting client and server using Mongo DB, Node.js and MySQL.
- Implemented client part of the Android and designed and implemented a game UI application.

Honors and Awards

College of Computing Travel scholarship for Grace Hopper Conference	SA,	2020
College of Computing Travel Scholarship for Richard Tapia Conference	SA,	2019
College of Computing Travel scholarship for Grace Hopper Conference	SA,	2019
CRA-W Grad Cohort for Women workshop scholarship	SA,	2019
The 1st Prize in C-Programming Camp, Handong Global University		2013
The 2nd Prize in Samsung Software Friendship		2014
Entrance Scholarship (awarded to 15% of all freshmen), Handong Global University	ity	2012

Teaching

Teaching Assistant CS 4460 Information Visualization	Fall 2020
Teaching Assistant CS 7450 Human-Computer Interact	$Summer\ 2020$
Teaching Assistant CS 7450 Information Visualization	Fall 2018
Teaching Assistant ECE10002-01 C-Programming	Fall 2015

Mentoring

Ting Yu, M.S HCI, Class of 2020, Qualitative and Quantitative Analysis 2021 Spring, Georgia Tech
Yu Fu, Ph.D. CS, Class of 2020, Qualitative coding & interrater reliability 2021 Summer, Georgia Tech

Professional Service

Reviewer

TVCG 2018

IV 2020

Programming Skills

Programming: Python, C/C++, Java, MATLAB, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, PHP, AJAX **Machine Learning:** Pandas, Scikit-learn, Plotly, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, NLTK, Gensim, Tensorflow, PyTorch

Data Visualization: D3.js, Three.js, Matplotlib, ggplot, Tableau

Database & Toolkits: Latex, JMP, Android, JSON, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS

Hayeong Song 3

Design & Research

Quantitative Research, Qualitative Research, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualization, Excel, Usability Testing, Survey, Benchmark Testing, Participant Recruiting, Interviews, Personas, Task Analysis, Affinity diagram, Observational study, Hypothesis testing, A/B testing, Log Analysis, Wireframing, Storyboards, User journey, Wizard-of-Oz

Coursework

Machine Learning

Natural Language Processing

Probabilistic Models

Introduction to Graduate Algorithms

Knowledge Based AI

Information Visualization

Human Computer Interact

User Interface Design & Evaluation

Network Analysis and Modeling

Network Systems

Foundation of Software Engineering

Educational Tech Foundations

Statistical Methods*

Math Foundation for Machine Learning*

(*)denotes in progress